UNITE Local 23-25 Memorabilia 6000/024 MB
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
UNITE Local 23-25 Memorabilia
1977-2004
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
UNITE Local 23-25
6000/024 MB
14.97 cubic feet
15 linear ft.
Memorabilia.
8239564
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, October 02, 2013
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 17, 2016
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 6000/024: UNITE Local 23-25 Records 6000/024 P: UNITE Local 23-25 Photographs 6000/024 PUBS: UNITE Local 23-25 Publications 6000/024 AV: UNITE Local 23-25 Audio-Visual Materials 6000/050: UNITE Local 10 and Local 23-25 Files 6000/050 AV: UNITE Local 10 and Local 23-25 Audio-Visual Materials 6000/050 MB: UNITE Local 10 and Local 23-25 Memorabilia 6000/050 P: UNITE Local 10 and Local 23-25 Photographs 6000/050 PUBS: UNITE Local 10 and Local 23-25 Publications 6000 AV: UNITE Audio-Visual Collection 6000 G: UNITE Posters 6000 MB: UNITE Memorabilia 6000 P: UNITE Photographs
Textile industry -- New York (State); International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union; Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees; Union of Needletrades, Industrial, and Textile Employees. Local 23-25 (New York, N.Y.); UNITE HERE (Organization)
8239564
- Banner 3'11" x 5'8" White background with red lettering "Local 23-25, ILGWU" and also a large ILGWU Union Label emblem. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Banner 2'6" x 3'11" Navy blue background with white lettering "Blouse Skirt and Sportswear Workers' Union"; yellow lettering "Local 23-25 ILGWU"; white letter "International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, AFL-CIO", with gold fringe along the bot (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Banner 3'3" x 8'1" Red background with white lettering "ILGWU First Aid Team" and a large Union label emblem at one end of banner. (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Banner 3'1" x 8'10" Red background with white lettering "UNITE! First Aid Team"; at one end it has a large "First Union Health Center-ILGWU" emblem. (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Banner 3'4" x 14'9" Navy blue background with white lettering "International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union"; with a large Union label emblem at one end of banner. (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Key chains 3 round gold pendants with the ILGWU emblem on the front, and "Local 23-25"; 2 plastic rectangular pendants "New York City Youthline, [phone no.]" white background with yellow and blue print (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Assorted buttons and pins push pins for "CLUW", "Hispanic Labor", AFL-CIO, and miscellaneous union buttons. (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Buttons "International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, Local 91"; "NO NAFTA"; "We are ONE in '91"; "Labor Supports CUNY, Don't Cut Our Class"; "ILGWU, UIOVD"; "United We Stand" (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Misc. buttons, mostly UNITE! "UNITE! For a fair contract (Chinese and Engl.); "Sweeney, Trumka, Chavez-Thompson, A New Voice For American Workers"; "Remember Tienanmen" (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Misc. buttons, and one badge all from UNITE!. "Doris Ling-Cohan for Civil Court"; "Int. Ladies Garment Workers Union, Union Made 23-25, AFL-CIO"; badge is "UNITE!, Delegate" (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Misc. button and push-pin from "Women's Suffrage Whakatu Wahine" attached to a small folder with information. Two "Official Volunteer Organizer" cards one in English, one in Spanish. One plastic ruler from the ILGWU. (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Glass plate White with gold trim and red lettering. "Chung Pak Community Center, Opening Ceremony, June 29, 1993, Sponsored by Citibank" (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Screen prints for flags in box 7 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Two paper hats White with "ILGWU" in red and a Union Label emblem (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Included in the box is a wooden block that has been hand carved. On one side is a ILGWU Union Label Emblem, on the other is written "To Vice President Jay Mazur, Good Luck, Ben Laboda, Local 99, June 3, 1977" (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Also included is a roll of 'Union Labels" used in clothing. (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Oversize box with a sign, posters, award, original artwork, and plaque. (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Sign 34 cm. x 46 cm. Gray with black lettering in Chinese and English. "Local 23-25 ILGWU, Political Department, Research/Education Department" (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Original artwork 31 cm. x 41 cm. By Jolanta Pienczykowski, and includes a note about the Artist's background (copy in accession file). "The Faces Behind The Union Label" is the title of the piece, it's a picture of a clothes hanger with a coat hangin (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Poster Chinese and English 28 cm. x 43 cm. "Mass Rally, Defend the Garment Industry." (Box 7, Folder 4)
- "Three Founders Award" 33 cm. x 39 cm. Certificate awarded to Shelley Appleton, Vice President of ILGWU, April 5, 1975, from Manhattan 28, American Veterans Committee. (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Plaque 36 cm. x 50 cm. "Local 23-25 NEWS" issue displayed on a plaque. Headlines for this issue are "Local Shows Strength in Labor Parade", Oct. 1981 issue. (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Poster 46 cm. x 58 cm. "Freedom House"; this is a poster with a picture from Tienanmen Square, Beijing and a letter from max M. Kampelman (Chairman, Freedom House) to President George Bush about Human Rights violations. (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Poster 44 cm. x 56 cm. "The CALL" Headlines read "Shirtwaist Strikers Present Facts of Great Struggle to the Public of New York City", in bottom left corner "Extra! Reissued by ILR Press"; "Literature of American Labor Series, Diary of a Shirtwai (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Poster 44 cm. x 56 cm. "Local 23-25 ILGWU" Christmas New Years Celebration (1990) on orange paper and signed by members at the gathering. 4 copies (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Poster 48 cm. x 60 cm. Hand made "Garment Industry Day Car Center of C.P.C." letters are silver and green, and it has little animals on it for decoration. (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Poster 46 cm. x 60 cm. Black lettering in Chinese. Red and white "UNITE" emblem on the bottom. (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Poster 56 cm. x 71 cm. Hand made by children. Colored and written with crayons, "The Wizard of OZ On Ice" a thank you note to Mrs. May Ying Chen from "you friends at GIDCC" (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Calendar 46 cm. x 60 cm. 1993 "There was an old woman who lived in a shoeshe was a member of the ILGWU". The picture on the front is of children popping out of a shoe. (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Scarf Made out of ILGWU Union Label material. (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Flag triangle in shape Yellow "CLUW, Chinese Committee" (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Flag triangle in shape Orange (two sided) "Enforce Labor Laws UNITE!" on one side, the other side is in Chinese (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Name plate for May Chen (gold with black lettering) 3"x10" (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Hang tags, letter -- Letter about the hang tags, and 9 hang tags -- red with blue lettering, blue with white stripes on one end -- "UNITE! Proudly made in New York" -- [10 tags] 2001 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- UNITE!, bumper sticker; SOLIDARITY, Local 23-25 UNITE! (convention fans) [4] (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Award/Plaque -- NYC Apala Chapter honors May Yin Chin (sp) on your election as 1st Woman Bus. Manager to N.Y. Metropolitan Area Joint Board 9"x12" 2004 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Poem -- "The Union Representative" (May the good Lord grant him strength) (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Award/Plaque -- Community Appreciation Award presented to UNITE!, 1996, Chinese-American Planning Council, Inc.. 9"x12" 1996 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Award/Plaque -- 1999 Community Appreciation Award presented to UNITE! In recognition of your outstanding contribution -- 8"x10" -- 1999 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Award/Plaque -- Community Partnership Award, 2004, presented to Local 23-25 Unite -- 8"x10" -- 2004 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Award/Plaque -- Community Appreciation Award presented to UNITE! In recognition of your outstanding contribution -- 8"x10" -- 1997 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Award/Plaque -- In recognition of International Women's Day and Women's History Month, the Chinese Chapter of CLUW. 9"x12" -- 2004 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Award/Plaque -- The Chinese-American Planning Council, Inc. presents the 2002 Community Appreciation Award to UNITE! 6"x8" Marble and wood -- 2002 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Award -- 7th Fannie Lou Hamer Award is conferred upon May Ying Chen -- 8.5"x11" 1991 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Push pin/buttons -- One Hundred Years Local 10, 2002 [4] -- 2002 (Box 8, Folder 13)
- book/Autograph(?) -- Red book with Chinese figures in gold on the cover, the inside has signatures written on the pages (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Award -- Our salute to United Local 23-25 for the partnership in service and ministry to the Chinatown Community -- 8.5"x11" (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Award/Plaque -- Shaped like New York State -- Presented to May Ying Chen, May 21, 1997, In recognition of her outstanding contributions on behalf of the Ethnic Labor 1997 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Award/Plaque -- Hispanic Labor Committee, New York City Central Labor Council, AFL-CIO, Presented to May Ying Chen -- 11.5"x14.5" (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Award/Plaque -- Metro New York, Labor Communications Council, First Award, Presented to UNITE 23-25 News -- 11.5"x14.5" (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Award/Plaque -- Metro New York, Labor Communications Council, First Award, Presented to UNITE VOICE -- 11.5" x14" (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Award/Plaque -- Gouverneur Healthcare Services Special Recognition Award Presented to Local 23-25 -- 10.5"x13" (Box 9, Folder 5)
- "NOT 1(cent) For Sweatshops Keep Postal Uniforms Sweat-Free" ---- Stamps (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Award -- (Plastic 'shooting star' award)- CLUW - May Chen Executive Director, Local 23-25 UNITE-Formally ILGWU, November 11, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Award -- Every Kid Deserves a Y -- In appreciation to Unite Local 23-25 Bronze Sponsor, Chinatown YMCA, 25th Anniversary Dinner, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Paper weight -- Friend of Felix W. Ortiz Award to May Chen, 6/18/98, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Rubber stamps -- Some stamps have wooden handles with organizations names and others are date stamps [22] (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Rubber stamps (list) Do Not Bend; Nebraska Service Center; U.S. Department of Justice Immigration and Naturalization Service; Copy; Draft (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Rubber stamps (list) US Immig. & Natz. Service; Immigration and Naturalization Service; National Visa Center; Priority Mail; Received; date stamp (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Rubber stamps (list) Yat Ding Ho Restaurant; Immigration and Naturalization Service, Texas Service Center; UNITE Immigration Project; US Department of Justice, Immigration and Naturalization Service; Personal (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Rubber stamps (list) US Immig. & Natz. Service; Original Please Return; Train 7 to Shea Stadium (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Banner Nylon 33"x90" -- "Local 62-32 UNITE!" [Red and White letters on Blue nylon, scalloped bottom with fringe] (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Banner burlap 3'x113" -- "Don't Buy GUESS! GUESS USES SWEATSHOPS" [burlap with Black, Blue, Red painted lettering] (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Banner cotton sheet 3'6"x12'4" -- "ASIAN LABOR COMMITTEE; NYC Central Labor Council AFL-CIO" [White cotton sheet, Red, Blue painted letters, Chinese characters] (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Banner vinyl 3'6"x12'4" -- "UNITE! SPRING HEALTH CONFERENCE" [Red vinyl with White vinyl/adhesive lettering, also Chinese characters] (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Banner cotton 5'6"x12' -- "Textbook Scholarship Awards Ceremony; UNITE HERE!; NY METRO AREA JT. BD., Textbook Scholarship Program" [some Chinese characters and Spanish on bottom of banner; White cotton with Blue nylon around the outside, stenciled (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Banner vinyl 2'8"x18'7" -- "Protect Garment Workers Rights" [Chinese characters and Spanish; Red vinyl with White vinyl/adhesive lettering] (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Banner cotton sheet 4'x20' -- ASIA LABOR FESTIVAL" [White cotton sheet with Red and Blue tape for lettering, Chinese characters along bottom; lettering stapled to material, most lettering falling off banner] (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Banner vinyl 2'8"x18'7" -- "STOP SWEATSHOPS" [Red vinyl with White vinyl/adhesive lettering, also Chinese characters and Spanish] (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Banner vinyl 2'9"x11'8" -- "Garment Industry Day Care Center of Chinatown; Annual Fund Raising Dinner" [White vinyl with Red vinyl/adhesive lettering] (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Broadside 18" dia. -- Round, "UNITE HERE!" [White with Black and Red letters]; Broadside 18"x24" -- "Not 1{cent} for SWEATSHOPS, KEEP POSTAL UNIFORMS SWEAT-FREE; UNITE!" [White with Red lettering]; Broadside 17"x24" -- "Who made your shoes?" [Pi (Box 15, Folder 1)
- Award 12"x16" -- 1999 Distinguished Services Award to May Ying Chen; Broadside 16"x20" -- Picture with wording "Bridge Builder" and below it has "The New York Civic Participation Project; 2005 Bridge Builder Award; Presented to: May Y. Chen", 2004 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Broadside 13"x17" -- Thank You, City of Hope [article on Edgar O. Romney]
- Proclamation 14x24 -- "The Council, City of New York ProclamationLocal 23-25 UNITE" 2004 (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Assorted banners and flags (Box 17, Folder 1)
  2 red vinyl flags - [UNITE! And ENFORCE LABOR LAWS] -Chinese on one side and English on one side; Banner - White cotton, Letters stenciled w/black and blue paint - [WIPEOUT SWEATSHOPS; UNITE! AFL-CIO] - 96x134; White cotton, Letters stenciled w/black and blue paint - [WIPEOUT SWEATSHOPS; UNITE! AFL-CIO] - 42x96; Banner - light blue cloth - [UNITE! GARMENT WORKERS'] - Chinese characters, Letters stenciled with paint (very dirty) - 28x100
- Banners - see list below (Box 17, Folder 2)
  Light blue cotton "UNITE! GARMENT WORKERS' CENTER" Chinese characters, letters are stenciled with paint 28"x100" (very dirty); White cotton "WIPE OUT SWEATSHOPS UNITE! AFL-CIO" letters stenciled with black paint 42"x96"; White cotton "WIPE OUT SWEATSHOPS UNITE! AFL-CIO" letters stenciled with black paint 42"x134"; red vinyl Triangle shaped white lettering [2] one flag "Enforce Labor Laws"; one flag "UNITE" both flags have Chinese characters on flip side
- Mapfolder with oversize items (Box 18, Folder 1)